Resume

Ryan Morshead is a software engineer with experience across the stack as a learner and a leader in open source and enterprise. Having worked on projects from their inception into the long decline he believes the written and verbal communication of one's work form the foundation of its sustainability.

Technical Skills

	Advanced	Intermediate	Novice
Languages	Python	Javascript	Go, C++
Frameworks	Flask, Asyncio	React	
Tools	Git, PyTest, Sphinx	Docker, Jenkins, Travis Cl	Kubernetes
Databases		SQL (Postgres), Redis	
Clouds			Google Cloud Platform, AWS

Work Experience

Senior Software Engineer | Cisco Smart Licensing

Jul 2018 - Present - Brought onto Cisco's Engineering Licensing team as the first hire on a new project intended to serve Cisco's licensing needs for its present and future cloud products.

 Delivered software used by Cisco's new DNA Center and future products for years to come.

- Developed a Python flavor Cisco's Smart Licensing software from the ground up.
- · Designed goals and deadlines for long term projects.
- · Screened, interviewed, recommended, and trained new hires.

Platforms Engineer | Primer Al

Nov 2017 - Apr 2018 - Part of a growing team of engineers working to support data scientists working to develop machine learning solutions to text based problems.

- · Resident Pythonista.
- · Added backend REST API features and expanded test coverage.
- · Built and deployed simple micro service using Python and Flask.
- · Learned React on the job to aide in developing frontend components.
- Introduced teams to Jupyter as a tool for reproducible and shareable science.

Engineer in Test | Apple Maps

Jul 2017 - Nov 2017 - One of two engineers brought on to develop a UI test automation framework for a map editor used in the production pipeline for Apple Maps.

- Developed a framework around Selenium for easily testing UI applications.
- · Expanded test coverage to relieve manual testers.
- · Communicated with core devs to ensure products meet expectations.

Owned Projects

O iDOM - Python for the Web

Gives Python developers the power to create interactive web applications without writing a single line of Javascript. iDOM was originally inspired by Jupyter Widgets and Nteract's VDOM, however it breaks from both by allowing live updates to substantially sized frontend views.

Spectate - MVC for Python

A library for Python 2 and 3 that can track changes to mutable data types. With spectate complicated protocols for managing updates don't need to be the outward responsibility of a user and can instead be done "automagically" in the background. For instance, syncing the state between a server and client can controlled by spectate so user's don't have to.

Maintained Projects

Traitlets - IPython & Jupyter

Traitlets is a pure Python library for enforcing strong typing, observing changes to tracked data, and reading configuring values from files or from command line arguments. Traitlets powers the configuration system of IPython and Jupyter and the declarative API of IPython's interactive widgets.

Education



Recommondations

His knowledge of the inner workings of Python are easily some of the best I've seen... he is also one of the most genuine and cooperative people I have had the pleasure of working with.

in Alvin Yates - Former Manager